# **Mario Altagracia Jimenez**

Austin, TX | 512-994-1887 | Jimernez.io@gmail.com | Github.com/Toughee | https://toughee.github.io/Portfolio/

## **Summary**

Web Developer and Web Designer primarily focused on front end development. Experienced in building web applications emphasizing on responsive design and seamless user interfaces. Able to adjust myself in any team environment, possessing excellent communication skills, and capable of learning any tool or software needed complete any work assigned to me or my team. Frequent contributor to open source projects.

### **Work Experience**

Help Desk Agent

November 2017 – June 2018

Holiday Inn Express

Austin, TX

On site tech support for clients and incoming guests

- Resolved daily troubleshooting and networking issues
- Helped with 80% of connectivity and I.P related issues in a 7 month period
- Fixed browser issues for company desktop computers

Web Developer

November 2016 - June 2017

Durham, NC

*Code for America*Collaborative nonprofit position for the City of Durham, North Carolina

- Resolved U/I issues and refined U/X for the web application
- Launched complete web application for public use before deadline
- · Fixed website issues on a weekly basis

Assistant Data scientist

September 2015 - July 2016

San Juan, P.R

Sacred Heart University Library

Assistant position inside University's Library system

- Cataloged library items inside University's database
- Completed a weekly server inspection for all library items

#### Founder and Website Designer

November 2013 - May 2014

San Juan, P.R

Sx3 Consulting Firm

Independent Startup company primarily working with entertainment industry

- Worked on contract creating website designs, mockups and branding illustrations
- Collaborated with a national media platform to produce weekly client work
- Created successful branding strategies for different clients

#### **Technical Skills**

Web languages: HTML5, CSS3, Python, JavaScript

**Frameworks / Libraries:** Bootstrap, Django, React, Ruby on Rails

Version Control: Git

**CMS:** Wordpress, WooCommerce

**Servers and Databases:** MySQL, npm, PHP **Operating Systems:** macOS, Linux, Windows

Editing software: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

#### **Education**

### Sacred Heart University,

Aug 2011 – May 2016

B.A in **Advertising** 

San Juan, P.R

· Coursework in MySql databases and Web design

#### Volunteer work

Open Austin

June 2018 – Present